<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>



    <string name="kodikuthimala_string"> <center>
        <p>
            "kodi Kuthi Mala" is one of the main attraction at Malappuram District.It also known as the "Ootty of Malappuram".It is Hill station in Malappuram, where you can enjoy maximum at early morning or evening.
        </p>
        <p>
            This place is located in Vettathur and Thazhekode village of Perinthalmanna Taluk at 522m abobe sea level.It is a best place for trekking.
        </p>
        <p>
            The British hoisted their flag on this hilltop during a survey, thus getting the name Kodikuthimala. It is almost two decades ago that the hilltop started featuring on the tourism map of Kerala.[citation needed] Around 70 acres of land in this area is earmarked by the Tourism Department for various projects. Kodikuthimala, at an altitude of 1,713-ft above sea level, has a watch tower that is visited by tourists because of the vantage point it offers.

Trekking to the top of Kodikuthimala is a challenging task due to the varied topography of the hill.

The most common time to visit Kodikuthimala is between September to May.[citation needed] It is located 66 km from Palakkad.32 km from Malappuram, 9 km from Perintalmanna and 82 km from Calicut.
        </p>
        </center>
    </string>









    <string name="kottakkunnu_string">
        <center>
            <p>
                Kottakkunnu is a tourist destination in the state of Kerala located at Malappuram. Stationed right at the heart of the city, Kottakkunnu attracts large number of domestic as well as international tourists.
            </p>
            <p>
                Kottakkunnu, Known as Marine Drive of Malappuram is a hill garden. Kottakkunnu park contains an Open Air theater, Lalitha Kala Academy Art gallery, a water theme park, Adventure Park, Kids traffic park, Balloon Park, 16D Cinema. There is Water fountain and Laser show on every weekends and on festivals like Eid, Onam, New year eve etc. At Kottakkunnu one can see traces of the first fort built by the Zamorins. This tourism destination turned historic hill attracts lakhs of people per annum. This scenic table-top location is located at the crest of the Cantonment Hill near the District Collectorate in the heart of Malappuram city and 51 km from Kozhikode,12 km from Kottakkal, 25 km from Karipur Airport, 17 km from Angadipuram railway station and 29 km from Tirur railway station. Visitors are allowed up to 9pm. KSRTC Bus station located adjacent at Up Hill is the nearest bus station.
            </p>
            <p>
                Kottakkunnu being one of the high earning tourism destination in the state in the form of tickets, Tourism department has planned to make this one stop destination with all kind of entertainment. In 2015, tourism minister inaugurated Kottakkunnu Master plan of 100cr worth projects. Some of the components under the master plan has opened and many are underway.
            </p>
        </center>
    </string>






    <string name="nilambur_string">
        <center>
            <p>
                Nilambur is a municipality and a taluk in the Malappuram district of the Indian state of Kerala. It is located close to the Nilgiris range of the Western Ghats on the banks of the Chaliyar River. It is about 40 kilometers from Malappuram city and 24 kilometers from Manjeri on the Kozhikode–Gudalur road called CNG road (Calicut-Nilambur-Gudallur road).
            </p>
            <p>
                <u>Banglavu Kunnu</u>
Banglavu Kunnu (Bungalow Hill) is a bungalow located in Nilambur. It was built by the Imperial Forest Service in 1929 under British colonial rule. The original purpose of the bungalow was to see the approach of the Tippu Sultan's army via Nadukani Churam. It is situated in Chandakunnu near the Chaliyar River. The bungalow is surrounded by 100-year-old mahogany trees planted during the colonial times for their use as timber which were to be shipped to Portugal by the Portuguese. This practice was threatened by the resistance of the people of the Malabar region against the brutality of the Portuguese, which was stiff and ultimately resulted in victory.

The place is home to many varieties of flora and fauna. The major wild animals include the bonnet macaque, gray langur, wild boar, junglefowl, hare, and porcupine.

                <u>Nilambur Kovilakom</u>
Nilambur Kovilakom is a compound of several old palaces and a few new houses occupied by members of the old royal family of Nilambur. Some of the buildings are more than 200 years old.

                <u>Gateway of Nilambur</u>
The two kilometre beautiful forest road from Vadapuram bridge to Court road Nilambur is now popularly known as gateway of Nilambur. The road is surrounded by teak plantations on both sides and foot paths are now fully tiled to offer a nice experience to walk through. This place is now emerging as popular destination for a short break on the way to Ooty, Mysore and Bangalore.

                <u>Teak forest and plantations</u>
The Nilambur forests are also known for their tribal settlements, vast rain forests, waterfalls and the world's first Teak Museum. Just 2 kilometres (1.2 mi) from Nilambur town, there is the oldest teak plantation in the world, the Conolly's Plot. It is named after H. V. Conolly, the British Malabar district collector, who was instrumental in planting teak there. Chathu Menon, a forest officer, organised the planting of the saplings. Chathu Menon was laid to rest in the teak garden. Kannimari, the plantations' oldest teak tree, is another attraction. The plot extends across 2.31 hectares (5.71 acres) besides the Chaliyar river at the Aruvakode ferry.[1]

                <u>Teak Museum</u>
Main article: Teak Museum
On the Nilambur–Gudallur road, 4 kilometres (2.5 mi) away from the town, there's the Teak Museum, a sub-centre of the Kerala Forest Research Institute. The two storeyed building houses exhibits, articles and details of historic, aesthetic and scientific value, which give information on all aspects of the Teak trees, plantations, and so on.[1]

                <u>Conolly's Plot</u>
Conolly's Plot (misspelled as Canoli Plot and Canoly's Plot) named after Henry Valentine Conolly is the world's oldest teak plantations. It is 2 km from the Nilambur town, located in a place called Vadapuram near the government timber depot of Nilambur.

                <u>Important landmarks</u>
                <list>
                <ul>Nilambur - Shoranur Railway Line</ul>
                <ul>The Nilambur Co-operative College</ul>
                <ul>Amal College of Advanced Studies</ul>
                <ul>Teak Museum, teak forest and Connolly's Plot plantation</ul>
                <ul>New Amarambalam Reserved Forest</ul>
                <ul>Nilambur Elephant Reserve</ul>
                <ul>Manavedhan higher secondary school</ul>
                <ul>District hospital Nilambur</ul>
                <ul>Magistrate court Nilambur</ul>
                <ul>KSRTC sub depot Nilambur</ul>
                </list>
                <u>Naxalite threat</u>
Pothukal, Munderi and Karulai are strongholds of Naxalites, members of the Maoist Communist Party of India. In November 2016, two naxalites were killed near Karulai in an encounter with Kerala police. Naxalite leader Kappu Devaraj of Andhra Pradesh was included in the list of killed in the incident.[2] Villages like Mundakkadavu, Kalkullam and Uchakkulam near Karulai are threatened by Naxalite attacks. Naxalites visit the locality regularly and ask for food and shelter from the tribals. The police are also combing the area regularly but have not arrested any naxalites. On 27 September 2016, there was firing between the Maoists and the Kerala police in this area and no one was injured in this incident.
            </p>
        </center>
    </string>





    <string name="nedumkayam_string">
        <p>
            The moment you enter Nedumkayam Rainforest, you feel like the humdrum of daily life slowly melting away and the virgin scent of the forest taking over your senses. Around 15 km from Nilambur, it is loved by all who visit for the dense forest and lush greenery on display. People rave about the fresh air and clear water that flows through, along with rare species of flora and fauna. Nedumkayam Rainforest is part of the Nilgiri Biosphere Reserve and is one among the numerous reasons to visit Malappuram.
        </p>
        <p>
            Nedumkayam is 14 km from Nilambur town, in Malappuram district, Kerala, India. Nedumkayam is noted especially for its rich rain forests. The wooden resthouse built here by the British offers a panoramic view of the elephant and deer grazing in the forest nearby . One has to get prior permission from the Indian Forest Service to enter the forest zone. Heavy restrictions are imposed as a measure to save the existing forest land. An elephant taming center is also located here. Nilambur including Nedumkayam has been selected for being developed as Kerala's second ecotourism destination. It is very beautiful and very good tourist center.There is a huge demand for the last several years to create he Nilambur - Karulai - Silent Valley - Coimbatore road.
            <u>Road distances</u>
                <list>
                    <ul>Nilambur to Karulayi. 10 km</ul>
                    <ul>Karulayi to Nedungayam. 7 km</ul>
                    <ul>karulai to pookottumpadam 9 km</ul>
                    <ul>karulai to Edakkara 9 km</ul>
                </list>
        </p>

    </string>




    <string name="miniootty_string">

        <p>
            Arimbra Hills or Mini Ooty is a tourist spot near Malappuram. It is at a height of 1050 feet above sea level. The place attracts large number of visitors for its rolling hills and scenic views. The location got the nickname as it resembles Ooty, one of the famous hill stations in India. There are many stone crushers and plantations atop the hill. There is an old Harijan Colony on the western side of the hill.
        </p>
        <p>
            <u><head>How to Reach</head></u>
It can be reached by 4 km distance from Aravankara near Pookkottoor located in Malappuram - Calicut stretch of NH966. 11 km from Karathode located in Malappuram-Parappanangadi road (SH 72). There are several other minor roads that connects to the region from Pookotur, Musliyarangadi, Kottukara, Thottassery near Kondotty etc. An alternative route is available from Poolappis Junction near Oorakam on SH 72. Those who are coming from Calicut can access the hills from Colony road near Kondotty.
        </p>
        <p>
            <head><u>Hiking Spots</u></head>
Thiruvonamala, Poolappees, Muchikundu, Cheruppadi Mala, Kunnumpuram and Kakkad are suitable for hiking and also have fine viewpoints. You can see the runway of Kozhikode airport in full action from these viewpoints
        </p>
        <p>
            <head><u>History</u></head>
            Actually, Arimbra was a separate Revenue Village called Amsom at the time of British Raj. When the village head (Adhikari)was suspended by British Authorities due to some allegations against him, the Morayur village head (Adhikari) Kodithodika Valiya Ahammed Kutty Haji was given charge then. Later Arimbra merged to Morayur Revenue Village.[2]
        </p>

    </string>



    <string name="Kumaragiri_string">

        <p>
            Kumaragiri farm is an estate.Its located in Mankada,Malappuram District in the way of Perithalmanna - Manjeri Road.From Mankada Junction take a route to Kuttil road after Govt school Cheriyam, Mankada take immediate left to the small road(the estate road).If you have doubt ask any people the estate road,travel more than one kilometer,you will reach the main gate.In main gate you want to park the vechilcle.Then need to walk through the estate.In both side you can see rubber wood estate,after few minutes walk you can see a small water falls.
        </p>

    </string>







</resources>